Elmer Gertz Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Legal File, 1905-1992 (Box 13-300)
  - Professional, 1905-1992 (Box 18-300)
    - A & L Demirdjian, Inc. v. Korean Karate Inst. (Box 18)
      - Court documents, 1967-1968, undated, (3 folders)
    - Adult Education Council of Greater Chicago, Chicago, Ill.
      - College executive counselors, 1963, undated
      - Educational Opportunities Unlimited, 1958-1964, undated, (2 folders)
      - Samples, Ruhl M., 1961-1963
    - Agron v. New York, 1961
    - Aikens v. California See Container 54, Death penalty cases
    - Allen v. Gregory, 1963-1964, undated
    - Allen v. Meyer, 1955-1958, undated, (4 folders)
    - American Fed'n of Teachers v. National Educ. Ass'n, 1960-1963, undated, (3 folders) (Box 20)
    - American Jewish Conference v. City of Chicago, 1953-1988, undated, (5 folders)
    - American Society of Adlerian Psychology, 1950, undated
    - American Terrazzo and Tile Co.
      - 1950, (2 folders)
      - 1951-1952, undated, (3 folders) (Box 21)
    - Ammons, Eugene, 1958-1968, undated, (3 folders)
    - Amundson, Bea, 1971-1972, undated
    - In re Anastaplo, 1976-1982, undated
    - Andreloi v. Catholic Bishop
      - General, 1958-1970, undated, (5 folders)
      - Press, 1959-1965, (3 folders) (Box 22)
    - In re Application of the County Collectors
      - Background information, 1956-1972, undated, (3 folders)
      - Billing, 1972
      - Correspondence, 1969-1972
      - Court documents, 1967-1968, (2 folders)
    - Apter, Julia T., 1965-1978, undated
    - Asgar, Mohammet Ali, 1957-1968, undated
    - Associated Physicians of Cook County Hosp., Chicago, Ill., 1969-1972, undated, (2 folders)
    - Auditorium Theater Council, 1964 (Box 23)
    - Austin, Teller & Cooperman v. City of Chicago, 1961-1965, undated
    - Babcock v. Graham
      - Correspondence, 1960-1968, (3 folders)
      - Court documents, 1963-1965, undated
    - Badowicz v. Board of Junior College Dist. 515, 1967-1974, undated, (2 folders)
    - Barbe v. Chicago Am. Publishing Co., 1964-1965, undated
    - Barr, Stephen, 1945-1957, undated, (3 folders)
    - Bartimoccia v. Lindheimer, 1954-1964
    - Beaubien, Mark H., 1968 (Box 24)
    - Berger, Stanley, 1943-1967, undated
    - Berner, Joe, 1948-1950, (2 folders)
    - Bianco v. American Broadcasting Cos.
      - 1971-1979, (7 folders)
      - 1979-1980, (7 folders) (Box 25)
      - 1980-1983, (10 folders) (Box 26)
      - Undated, (5 folders) (Box 27)
    - Biehn v. Tess, 1946-1949, undated, (2 folders)
    - Bielski, Adalbert, 1963, undated
    - Bild v. Chicago Medical Soc'y, 1952-1962, undated, (7 folders) (Box 28)
    - Blanker v. City of Chicago, 1971
    - Blasi v. Department of Registration & Educ. (Box 29)
      - Background information, 1954-1967, undated, (5 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1965-1968
      - Court documents, 1967-1968, undated
    - Block, Robert J., 1978-1980, undated
    - Bloom, Roger, 1962-1967, undated, (4 folders)
    - Bose, Robert N., 1962-1969
    - Bourgeois, Adam, 1948-1962, undated (Box 30)
    - Bowen v. Hightower
      - Background information, 1970-1972, undated
      - Billing, 1972-1973
      - Correspondence, 1972-1973
      - Court documents, 1972-1973, undated
    - Boxer v. Gregory
      - Background information, 1961-1967, undated
      - Correspondence, 1962-1966, undated, (5 folders)
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, undated, (2 folders); (6 folders) (Box 31)
        - General
          - 1963, (2 folders)
          - 1963-1965, undated, (5 folders) (Box 32)
    - Braga, Joseph, 1971-1974, undated
    - Branch v. Texas See Container 54, Death penalty cases
    - Bromberg v. Ditkowsky, 1976-1978
    - Bruhn v. Vaselopulos, 1961-1963, undated, (2 folders)
    - Bumpers v. North Carolina, 1967-1968, undated
    - Burghardt, Hugo, 1963-1964
    - Callaghan & Co. and National Found. of Health, Welfare & Pension Plans (arbitration case), 1967-1975, undated, (2 folders) (Box 33)
    - Camerarts Publishing Company, Sexology magazine contract, 1964
    - Camerarts Publishing Co. v. Prather
      - Background information
        - Books
          - 1952-1961, (4 folders)
          - 1962-1964, (5 folders) (Box 34)
          - 1964-1965, undated, (5 folders) (Box 35)
        - Financial papers
          - 1962, (2 folders)
          - 1963-1964, (7 folders) (Box 36)
          - 1965-1966, (3 folders) (Box 37)
        - General, 1938-1973, undated, (5 folders)
      - Billing, 1968-1974
      - Correspondence
        - 1968-1969
        - 1970-1974, (2 folders) (Box 38)
      - Court documents
        - 1968-1973, (6 folders)
        - 1973-1974, undated, (7 folders) (Box 39)
    - Candy (Box 40)
      - Background information, 1964, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1964-1965
      - Press, 1964-1965
    - Caplin, Edna Layman
      - Correspondence
        - 1960, (4 folders)
        - 1960-1965, (4 folders) (Box 41)
      - Court documents, 1960-1962, undated, (2 folders)
      - General, 1960-1962, undated
    - Caplin, Otto P., 1956-1961
    - Capos v. Mid-America Nat'l Bank of Chicago, 1977
    - Carlson, Peter S., 1963-1966
    - Carner and Charles C. Thomas Publisher, 1965-1972 (Box 42)
    - Central Furniture Mart, 1964-1971
    - Chase, Merrill, 1978, undated
    - Chiakulas v. Chicago Bd. of Educ., 1965-1966, undated
    - Chicago Hous. Auth. cases
      - Correspondence, 1948-1952, undated, (3 folders)
      - Court documents
        - 1948-1950, (3 folders)
        - 1950, undated, (4 folders) (Box 43)
      - General, 1948-1952, (2 folders)
    - Cinecom Corp., 1971, undated
    - City of Chicago v. Camerarts Publishing Co.
      - Correspondence, 1964-1967, (2 folders)
      - Court documents, 1964, undated
      - General, 1962-1966, (2 folders)
    - City of Chicago v. Compton, 1961-1965, (2 folders) (Box 44)
    - Clark v. Holmes
      - Background information, 1964-1973, undated, (4 folders)
      - Billing, 1970-1973
      - Correspondence
        - 1968-1969, (3 folders)
        - 1970-1974, undated, (6 folders) (Box 45)
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, undated, (2 folders)
        - General
          - 1968
          - 1969-1973, (9 folders) (Box 46)
          - Undated, (2 folders); (4 folders) (Box 47)
    - Cohen, Osna, 1958, 1967, undated
    - Coles v. United States
      - Background information, 1970, undated
      - Correspondence, 1967-1970, undated
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1966-1968
        - General, 1968-1970, undated, (3 folders)
    - In re The Complete Marquis De Sade (Box 48)
      - Background information, 1953-1969, undated, (4 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1965-1970, undated, (4 folders)
      - Court documents, 1967-1969, undated
    - Contreras v. Citibank
      - 1977-1988, (3 folders)
      - 1988-1991, undated, (6 folders) (Box 49)
    - Coons v. Chicago Hous. Auth., 1946-1949
    - Cooperman v. City of Chicago
      - Background information, 1961-1962, undated
      - Correspondence, 1961-1965, undated
      - Court documents, 1961-1965, undated
    - Crampton v. Ohio
      - Background information, 1969-1971, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1970-1972, undated
      - Court documents, 1969-1970, (2 folders) (Box 50)
    - Crane Paper Stock Co. v. Chicago & N.W. Ry., undated
    - Crump, Paul, 1969-1977, undated, (2 folders)
    - Cusack v. Teitel Film Corp.
      - Background information
        - General
          - 1956-1966, (4 folders)
          - 1967-1968, undated, (3 folders) (Box 51)
        - Oral argument, 1966-1967, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1966-1968, undated, (3 folders)
      - Court documents (Box 52)
        - 1965-1969, (8 folders)
        - Undated, (3 folders) (Box 53)
    - Davis v. Attic Club, 1905, 1960-1982, undated, (5 folders)
    - Davis v. Healy
      - Background information, 1962-1964, undated
      - Correspondence, 1960-1964
      - Court documents, 1961-1964, undated (Box 54)
    - In re Dean v. Illinois
      - Background information, 1941-1968, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1955-1967, undated, (2 folders)
      - Court documents, 1964-1967, undated
    - Death penalty cases See also same series, names of individual cases
      - Background information, 1971-1972, undated
      - Correspondence, 1971-1972, undated
      - Court documents, 1971
      - Press, 1971-1972
    - Desai v. Hersh, 1983, undated (Box 55)
    - Dewey v. Paul, 1968-1969, undated
    - Dixon v. Cahill, 1963-1973, undated, (2 folders)
    - Doe v. Small See also Container 207, Rohrer v. Small
      - 1989, (4 folders); (5 folders) (Box 56)
      - 1990-1991, undated, (9 folders) (Box 57)
    - Dreikurs v. Illinois
      - Background information, 1954-1958, undated
      - Correspondence, 1956-1959, undated, (3 folders) (Box 58)
      - Court documents, 1956-1959, undated, (2 folders)
    - E. & J. Gallo Winery v. American Fed'n of Teachers, 1975
    - Eberheart v. Georgia, 1974-1975
    - Educational Communications, 1975-1977, undated
    - Eisenschiml, Otto, copyright matter with Ralph G. Newman, 1947, (2 folders)
    - Eisenschiml v. Fawcett Publications (Box 59)
      - Background information, 1935-1958, undated, (8 folders)
      - Billing, undated
      - Correspondence (Box 60)
        - 1953-1957, (9 folders)
        - 1957-1958, (3 folders) (Box 61)
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1936-1957, undated, (2 folders)
        - General
          - 1953-1956, (5 folders)
          - 1956-1958, undated, (9 folders) (Box 62)
    - Eisenschiml v. Parade Publications, 1955 (Box 63)
    - Elbert v. Board of Educ. of Lanark Community Unit School Dist. 305, 1971-1981, undated, (6 folders)
    - Eley v. Cahill, 1970
    - English, Charles, 1965-1967
    - Environmental Protection Agency v. Granite City Steel Co., 1970-1971, undated
    - Epton, Bernard E., 1983-1984 (Box 64)
    - Etscheid v. Police Bd., 1943-1964, undated, (8 folders)
    - Fanny Hill, 1960-1965, undated, (5 folders) (Box 65)
    - Farnsworth v. Tribune Co.
      - Background information
        - 1928-1970, (4 folders)
        - Undated, (4 folders) (Box 66)
      - Billing, 1968, undated
      - Correspondence
        - 1962-1967, (4 folders)
        - 1968-1970, undated, (2 folders) (Box 67)
      - Court documents
        - Depositions, 1961-1968, undated, (4 folders)
        - Exhibits, 1961-1968, undated
        - General (Box 68)
          - 1962-1968, (9 folders)
          - 1969, undated, (9 folders) (Box 69)
        - Jury instructions, undated (Box 70)
    - Feldman, Benjamin, 1966-1967
    - Field Enters. and Milgo-Idab Corp., 1969-1973
    - Filler, Louis, 1959-1971
    - Fleishour v. United States
      - Background information
        - 1954-1967, undated, (6 folders)
        - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 71)
      - Correspondence, 1961-1970, undated, (6 folders)
      - Court documents
        - 1963
        - 1964-1966, (5 folders) (Box 72)
        - Undated, (3 folders); (4 folders) (Box 73)
    - Fohrman Motors v. Chew, 1966, (3 folders)
    - Founding Church of Scientology v. American Medical Ass'n, 1975-1976
    - Fowler v. North Carolina, 1971-1976, undated, (5 folders) (Box 74)
    - Freidman v. Bantam Books
      - Background information, 1968, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 75)
      - Correspondence, 1968-1969, undated
    - Freiwald v. Salvato See also Containers 102-103, Illinois ex rel. Freiwald v. Morrisey, and Container 247, Stuck v. Salvato
      - Background information, 1955-1969, undated
      - Correspondence, 1967-1972, (2 folders)
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1968, undated
        - General, 1968-1972, undated, (4 folders)
    - Furman v. Georgia See Container 54, Death penalty cases (Box 76)
    - Galenti v. Field Enters.
      - Background information, 1957-1960, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1960-1961, undated
      - Court documents, 1960-1961, undated, (5 folders)
      - Press, 1960-1961, (3 folders)
    - Garcia v. DeSutter (Box 77)
      - Background information, undated, (3 folders)
      - Billing, undated
      - Correspondence, 1968-1972, undated, (2 folders)
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1968
        - General, 1968-1972, undated, (4 folders)
    - Gates, Norma, 1966, undated
    - General Gas & Oil Co. v. American Oil Co.
      - Background information, 1961-1965
      - Correspondence, 1962-1966, undated, (2 folders) (Box 78)
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, undated, (2 folders)
        - General, 1961-1966, undated, (6 folders)
    - Gertz, Marvin, 1972-1976 (Box 79)
    - Gingiss Bros., Inc. v. Fawcett Publications, 1952-1953
    - Goldberg, Barry J., 1969-1970
    - Goldberg, Marshall, Jr., 1970
    - Goldberg v. Liston
      - Background information, 1963-1971, undated, (4 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1964-1971, undated, (3 folders)
      - Court documents
        - Depositions
          - 1964
          - 1965, (2 folders) (Box 80)
        - Exhibits, 1964-1969, undated, (3 folders)
        - General
          - 1964-1969, (3 folders)
          - 1969-1971, undated, (6 folders) (Box 81)
        - Transcripts, 1969, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 82)
    - Goloff, Arthur W., 1963-1966, undated, (3 folders)
    - Gordon, Julie P., 1977-1980, undated, (3 folders)
    - Gray, William Louis
      - 1965-1968, (4 folders)
      - 1968-1972, undated, (4 folders) (Box 83)
    - Greenbaum, Wolff, & Ernst v. Aldington, 1956
    - Greenholdt v. Illinois Bell Tel. Co., 1982, undated
    - In re Gumm, 1966
    - Hall, Jeanne, 1960
    - Hanlon, Tom, 1967
    - Harris v. Continental Ill. Nat'l Bank & Trust Co.
      - Background information, 1967-1971, undated
      - Billing, 1972, undated
      - Correspondence, 1969-1972
      - Court documents, 1967-1971, undated, (3 folders)
    - Harrison v. Ashford (Box 84)
      - Background information, 1970-1971, undated
      - Correspondence, 1971-1972, undated
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1970-1971
        - General, 1971-1972
    - Hasegawa v. Northwestern Univ., 1970-1983, undated, (3 folders)
    - Hauswald v. Board of Educ. of Community High School Dist. 217, 1957
    - HBKS Interstate Restaurant Corp. v. Johnny's Am. Inn
      - Background information
        - 1964-1971, (2 folders)
        - Undated (Box 85)
      - Billing, 1971
      - Correspondence, 1970-1971
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1969-1971, undated, (2 folders)
        - General, 1969-1971, undated, (4 folders)
    - Hecht v. American Fed'n of Teachers
      - Background information, undated
      - Correspondence, 1968-1970, undated
      - Court documents, 1968-1970, undated, (3 folders) (Box 86)
    - Heller, Selig, 1965-1972, undated See also Container 7, same heading
    - Henderson v. North Carolina, 1974-1975, undated
    - Henry, Paul, 1953-1966, undated, (5 folders)
    - Hergenrother, William J., 1966-1967, undated
    - Herzenberg v. Illinois Inst. of Technology
      - Background information
        - 1956-1963, (2 folders)
        - 1964-1967, undated, (5 folders) (Box 87)
      - Correspondence, 1967, undated
      - Court documents, 1967, undated
    - Higgs, Sandra, 1989, undated, (3 folders)
    - Hodes Motors v. Chrysler Corp. (Box 88)
      - Background information, 1950, undated
      - Correspondence, 1948-1952
      - Court documents, 1946-1952, undated, (3 folders)
    - Hohmeier v. Leyden Community High School Dist. 212, 1988-1992, undated, (2 folders)
    - Hostrop v. Board of Junior College Dist. 515, 1975-1978
    - Howard v. Sears
      - Background information
        - 1966-1969, (1 folder)
        - 1970-1972, undated, (3 folders) (Box 89)
      - Billing, 1972, undated
      - Correspondence, 1971-1972, undated
      - Court documents
        - 1971-1972, (3 folders)
        - 1972, undated, (3 folders) (Box 90)
      - Press, 1972, undated
    - Hubacker v. Jordan, 1966-1968, undated
    - Hulman v. Lawn Sav. & Loan Ass'n
      - Background information, 1968-1969, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1968-1969, (2 folders)
      - Court documents, 1968-1969, undated, (3 folders) (Box 91)
    - Humphrey Chevrolet v. City of Evanston, 1956-1957, undated
    - Hyde Park redevelopment projects, Chicago, Ill.
      - 1952-1963, (7 folders)
      - Undated (Box 92)
    - Illinois v. Allen
      - Background information, 1957-1969, undated, (2 folders)
      - Billing, 1970-1972, undated
      - Correspondence, 1969-1971, (2 folders)
      - Court documents, 1969-1971, undated, (3 folders)
    - Illinois v. Board of Educ., 1960, undated
    - Illinois v. Butler
      - 1969-1970, (2 folders)
      - 1970, undated (Box 93)
    - Illinois v. Croft, 1969-1970
    - Illinois v. Gant, 1968-1971, undated
    - Illinois v. Hill
      - General
        - 1911-1978, (6 folders)
        - 1978-1979, (10 folders) (Box 94)
        - 1979-1982, (5 folders) (Box 95)
        - Undated, (6 folders); (8 folders); (2 folders) (Box 96, Box 97)
      - Transcripts
        - 1975-1977, (3 folders)
        - Undated, (1 folder); (3 folders); (4 folders); (2 folders) (Box 98, Box 99, Box 100)
    - Illinois v. Kahn
      - Background information, 1967-1969, undated, (3 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1969, undated
      - Court documents, 1969, undated
      - Press, 1969, undated, (2 folders)
    - Illinois v. Kamsler, 1966, undated
    - Illinois v. Lastick (Box 101)
      - Background information, 1967-1968, undated
      - Correspondence, 1967-1968, undated
      - Court documents, 1967-1968, undated
    - Illinois v. Lewis, 1980-1982, undated, (2 folders)
    - Illinois v. Marshall, 1970, undated
    - Illinois v. Romaine, 1966-1967, (2 folders)
    - Illinois v. Sherman
      - Background information
        - 1963-1967, undated, (3 folders)
        - Undated (Box 102)
      - Correspondence, 1964-1967, undated
      - Court documents, 1967, undated
    - Illinois v. Steinborn, 1962-1968, undated, (2 folders)
    - Illinois ex rel. Freiwald v. Morrissey See also Container 75, Freiwald v. Salvato
      - Background information
        - Closing argument, 1969, undated
        - General
          - 1965-1969, undated, (5 folders)
          - Undated (Box 103)
        - Notes on trial proceedings, 1969, undated
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1968-1969, undated, (2 folders)
        - General, 1968-1969, undated, (2 folders)
    - Independent Prods. Corp. v. Schoenstadt Theatres, 1956-1959
    - Independent Voters of Ill. v. Kusper, 1972, (1 folder) (Box 104)
    - Indiana Univ. v. Publishers Dev. Corp.
      - Background information, 1958-1970, undated
      - Correspondence, 1960-1970, undated
      - Court documents, 1961-1963, undated, (3 folders)
    - Indiana Univ. Press v. Saturday Evening Post, 1962-1963
    - Ingram v. License Appeal Comm'n
      - 1968-1969, (2 folders)
      - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 105)
    - Insull v. New York-World Tel. Corp.
      - Background information, 1934, 1950-1959, undated, (3 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1958-1960, (3 folders)
      - Court documents
        - 1957-1959, (4 folders)
        - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 106)
    - Intertecnica, S.R.L. v. Intercontinental Trade Corp. 1965-1972, undated, (5 folders)
    - Jackson v. Georgia See Container 54, Death penalty cases
    - Jarrett v. Illinois Bell Tel. Co., 1961-1967, undated
    - In re Jerome (Box 107)
      - Background information
        - Counts 1 and 2, Kenneth P. Palicki, 1957-1962, undated, (2 folders)
        - Count 3, Rose Menard, 1962-1963, undated
        - Count 4, Anna M. Trzebiatowski, 1949-1964, undated
        - General, 1960-1964, undated, (3 folders)
      - Correspondence
        - 1961-1963, (3 folders)
        - 1964-1965, (2 folders) (Box 108)
      - Court documents, 1961-1964, undated, (5 folders)
    - Johnkol, Inc. v. License Appeal Comm'n
      - Background information
        - 1965-1969, (3 folders)
        - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 109)
      - Correspondence, 1968-1969
      - Court documents
        - 1968-1969, (4 folders)
        - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 110)
    - Johnson v. Moore, 1970-1971
    - Johnson v. Mutual of Omaha, 1965, (3 folders)
    - Jorgensen v. Harlas, 1966-1967
    - Kamm v. Law Bulletin Publishing Co., 1984-1985
    - Karp, Haskell, 1967-1972
    - Kelber v. Board of Jewish Educ., 1978-1982, undated, (2 folders)
    - Kemp, James Hal (Box 111)
      - Correspondence, 1963-1967, undated, (5 folders)
      - General, 1963-1965, undated, (2 folders)
    - Kerner, Anton, 1978-1979, undated
    - Kerr v. City of Chicago, 1968-1970, undated, (2 folders)
    - Kiepura v. Local 1091, United Steelworkers, 1959-1974, undated, (10 folders) (Box 112)
    - Kiiskila v. Nichols (Box 113)
      - Background information, 1950-1971, undated, (2 folders)
      - Billing, 1971-1973
      - Correspondence, 1969-1973, undated
      - Court documents, 1968-1972, undated, (5 folders)
    - Kincy v. Wilson
      - Background information, 1966-1967, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1964-1967, undated
      - Court documents, 1964-1968, undated, (6 folders) (Box 114)
    - Kobthum v. Stackler
      - Background information, 1972-1977, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence
        - 1970-1974, (2 folders)
        - 1975-1977, undated, (4 folders) (Box 115)
      - Court documents
        - 1975-1976, (7 folders)
        - Undated, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 116)
    - Kol, Stuart, 1967, undated
    - Kosich, Marie Ann, 1957-1966, undated
    - Kostrubala, Thaddeus L.
      - Roman Catholic Archdiocese of Chicago, 1966-1968, (2 folders)
      - Stone-Brandel Center, 1965-1968, undated, (4 folders)
    - Kovler, Marjorie, 1966-1967, undated
    - Lambert v. City of Chicago, 1960-1967
    - Larkin v. G. P. Putnam's Sons, 1938, 1963, (4 folders) (Box 117)
    - Larson v. American Medical Ass'n
      - Background information, 1954-1969, undated
      - Correspondence, 1964-1972, undated, (2 folders)
      - Court documents, 1969, undated, (2 folders)
    - Law school assistants, 1963-1967, undated, (2 folders)
    - Lazarus, Maurice J., 1970
    - Leal v. Krajewski, 1983-1986, undated, (10 folders) (Box 118)
    - Lebans, James E., 1969-1970
    - Leopold, Nathan Freudenthal, Don Murray film, 1963-1964
    - Leopold v. Levin (Box 119)
      - Background information
        - General, 1953-1970, undated, (8 folders)
        - Illinois v. Leopold
          - Psychiatric reports, 1924, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 120)
          - Transcripts, 1924, (5 folders); (7 folders) (Box 121, Box 122)
        - Miscellaneous cases (Box 123)
          - 1942-1965, (7 folders)
          - 1966-1968, undated, (4 folders) (Box 124)
        - Notes, 1957-1960, undated
      - Correspondence
        - 1954-1958, (4 folders)
        - 1958-1960, (11 folders) (Box 125)
        - 1961-1965, (9 folders) (Box 126)
        - 1966-1970, undated, (7 folders) (Box 127)
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits
          - 1956-1966, (3 folders)
          - Undated, (1 folder) (Box 128)
        - General
          - 1959-1961, (8 folders)
          - 1962-1965, (8 folders) (Box 129)
          - 1965-1968, (7 folders) (Box 130)
          - 1968-1970, (5 folders) (Box 131)
          - Undated, (4 folders); (5 folders) (Box 132)
      - Press
        - 1957-1964, (5 folders)
        - 1965-1970, undated, (2 folders) (Box 133)
    - Les Girls Productions, Hollywood, Calif., 1968
    - Lim, Roland A., 1964-1965, undated
    - Lloyd, Alice J., and Johnnie Bernice Sumerall, 1939-1962, undated, (7 folders)
    - Local Union 1427, Int'l Bhd. of Elec. Workers and Commonwealth Edison Co.
      - 1951-1957, (1 folder)
      - 1957, (7 folders) (Box 134)
      - 1957-1958, undated, (6 folders) (Box 135)
    - Lome v. United Press Int'l
      - Background information, 1963-1964, undated